avagotech.com 2016-06-09

# Cookies and your Privacy

This statement was last revised on September 5, 2013.

Avago Technologies provides this Privacy Statement to make you aware of our privacy practices and the choices you can make about how your personal information is collected and used, both on-line and off-line. To make this notice easy to access, it is available on the bottom of every Avago Technologies web page.

Customers are Avago Technologies most valuable asset. We recognize that building a long-term business relationship with you depends a great deal on trust. This trust begins with our commitment to respecting as well as protecting your privacy.

We've structured our web site so that you can visit us without identifying yourself or revealing any personal information. Throughout this Privacy Statement, personal information refers to any information that is unique to an individual, such as name, address, e-mail address, phone number, etc. If you do share your personal information with us, you can be assured that it will only be used to support your relationship with Avago Technologies.

Avago Technologies privacy statement covers 10 main areas which are listed below and described in details follows. Please keep in mind that our privacy practices may vary as required by local laws and policies.

**Content**

  1. Notice
  2. Choice
  3. Onward Transfer
  4. Access and Accuracy
  5. Security
  6. Oversight/Enforcement
  7. Tailoring E-Mail Communications and Web Experiences
  8. How Avago Technologies Uses Cookies
  9. Additional Information
  10. Customer Satisfaction Studies & Market Research Activities

#####  **1\. NOTICE**

**What information we collect**

During the course of your relationship with us, we may collect personal information to enable you to order products or services, download software updates, make requests, and register for customized communications programs. We may collect such personal information as your name, contact and billing information, transaction and credit card information. To tailor our subsequent communications to you and improve our products and services, we may ask you to provide information regarding your personal or professional interests, demographics, experience with our products and contact preferences. Personal information may be required to determine access eligibility for certain restricted parts of our site. Data collected on-line may be combined with information provided off-line.

**How we use the information**

Avago Technologies uses your personal information to better understand your needs and provide you with better service. Specifically, we use your personal information to help you complete a transaction, to communicate back to you, provide updates on service and benefits, and to personalize our web sites and communications with you. Credit card numbers are used only for payment processing and are not retained for other purposes. From time to time, we may also use your information to contact you for market research or to provide you with marketing information we think would be of particular interest. We will always give you the opportunity to opt-out of receiving such contact. If you would like to read more about how to opt-out, please follow the directions given below in the "Choice" section of this document. In addition, we will also follow local requirements where applicable.

**Whom we share the information with**

Avago Technologies does not sell, rent, or lease your personal information to others. Unless we have your permission or are required by law, we only share your personal information with other Avago Technologies entities or business partners who are acting on our behalf for the uses described above. Such Avago Technologies entities and business partners are governed by our privacy policies with respect to the use of this data and are bound by the appropriate confidentiality agreements.

#####  **2\. CHOICE**

Avago Technologies will not use or share your personal information in ways unrelated to the ones described above without first notifying you and offering a choice. We will also provide you the opportunity to let us know if you wish to opt-out at any time of certain or all contact from Avago Technologies, and we will do everything we can to honor such requests. This choice may be offered at the bottom of our on-line or off-line communications to you as well as on many of our web registration pages. If you have any difficulty exercising your choices, please send your request to [spgweb.response@avagotech.com](http://spgweb.response@avagotech.com/).

Your permission will always be secured first, should we ever decide to share your personal information with third parties that are not acting on our behalf and governed by our privacy policy.

#####  **3\. ONWARD TRANSFER**

Subject to your permission or as permitted by law, the personal information that you provide to us may be transferred within Avago Technologies across state or country borders. This may be done to consolidate data storage or to simplify the management of customer information.

#####  **4\. ACCESS AND ACCURACY**

Avago Technologies strives to keep your personal information accurate. We will provide you with access to your personal information, including making every effort to provide you with online access to your registration data so that you may review, update or correct your information at the Avago Technologies site where it was submitted. To protect your privacy and security, we will also take reasonable steps to verify your identity before granting you access or enabling you to make corrections. To access your personal information, return to the web page where you originally entered it and follow the instructions on that web page. If you cannot access your information on the web page, please telephone the nearest Avago Technologies Call Center for assistance, or send your request to [spgweb.response@avagotech.com](http://spgweb.response@avagotech.com/).

#####  **5\. SECURITY**

Avago Technologies is committed to ensuring the security of your personal information. To prevent unauthorized access or disclosure, maintain data accuracy, and ensure the appropriate use of personal information, we have put in place appropriate physical, electronic and managerial procedures to safeguard and secure it.

#####  **6\. OVERSIGHT/ENFORCEMENT**

Avago Technologies has an internal Global Customer Privacy Program. Its charter is to ensure appropriate privacy processes are in place in order to meet the practices outlined above.

#####  **7\. TAILORING E-MAIL COMMUNICATIONS AND WEB EXPERIENCES**

On occasion Avago Technologies may employ technologies that enable us to review which recipients have opened our e-mail communications and which links they have accessed in the message. This helps us to tailor our communications in our attempts to send you the most relevant information, as local laws and your preferences and permissions allow. As a registered user, we may also monitor your web browsing session while you are logged-in to Avagotech.com. In this way we will try to improve our web site through personalization to better meet your needs. Any such monitoring is done in accordance with local laws.

#####  **8\. HOW AVAGO TECHNOLOGIES USES COOKIES**

This cookies information page was last revised on September 5, 2013. It is a subset of the entire Avago Technologies Privacy Policy.

Avago Technologies uses cookies to help analyze web traffic, improve your overall web site experience and randomly assign visitors to specific servers to balance traffic loads. By gathering and remembering information with cookies, the web site can:

Tailor its operation to your needs, likes and dislikes

Enable automated log-in as a convenience for previously registered customers.

Prevent multiple survey requests during your visit(s) to our web sites.

Provide a better, more relevant web experience by letting us monitor what's working and what isn't through web site traffic analysis.

We want you to know that accepting a cookie in no way gives us access to your computer or any personal information about you, other than the data you choose to share with us.

**What are Cookies**

A cookie is a piece of information either stored temporarily in your browser's memory space (session cookie) or placed on your computer's hard drive (stored cookie). Cookies allow a web application to respond to you as an individual, without the need to identify you explicitly.

Session cookies disappear when you close your web browser.

Stored cookies tyically have a predetermined expiration date after which they disappear from your hard drive.

To learn more about cookies, please visit [AboutCookies.org](http://aboutcookies.org/); a guide designed to help you control and delete cookies.

**Cookies Used on Avago's Web Sites**

We have categorized our cookie use below. Note that some cookies are set by third parties which Avago does not control, so we can't ensure their cookies won't change over time.

  * Web Site Login

To provide acurate data, we identify users accessing myAvago, the login required area of avagotech.com.

  * Web Site Content

We use services from a number of companies to provide the most relevant and appropriate content for our visitors. Most of these services are used in specific areas of the site, meaning their cookies are set only when that content area is visited.

  * Social Networks

We utilize a number of social network services to enhance the sharing of our content.

  * Web Site Traffic Analysis

We can provide a more relevant web experience by monitoring what's working and what isn't through web site traffic analysis.

Adjusting Browser Cookie Settings

Cookies can be managed through functionality built into most web browsers (e.g. Microsoft Internet Explorer, Firefox, Chrome). They can be adjusted to notify you of cookie placement requests, ask for permission to accept them, or decline cookies completely. For information on how to adjust your web browser cookie settings, please visit:

Cookie/Web Site Questions

If you have any further questions or concerns, please .

#####  **9\. ADDITIONAL INFORMATION**

**Links to Third Party Web Sites**

Links to third party web sites are provided solely as a convenience to you. If you use these links, you will leave the Avago Technologies site. Avago Technologies has not reviewed all of these third party sites; does not control and is not responsible for any of these sites, their content or their privacy policies. Thus, we do not endorse or make any representations about them, or any information, software or other products or materials found there, or any results that may be obtained from using them. If you decide to access any of the third party sites linked to this site, you do so entirely at your own risk.

**Changes to the Privacy Statement**

All material changes to our Privacy Policy and practices will be posted on this page. The revision date shown at the top of the page will be updated accordingly.

**Contact Information**

Please e-mail questions or comments about our privacy practices to: spgweb.response@avagotech.com.

#####  **10\. CUSTOMER SATISFACTION STUDIES & MARKET RESEARCH ACTIVITIES**

**Product & Market Research @ Avago Technologies**

The market research process at Avago Technologies includes quantitative and qualitative studies on a wide range of topics. Quantitative studies may include surveys focused on overall markets, regions, applications, customers, or resellers. Qualitative studies include in-depth interviews, traditional in-person focus groups, or the use of online discussion boards or Blogs.

The idea behind all these processes is to learn what is important to you and tailor Avago Technologies products, systems, services, and support to exceed your expectations. If you are invited to participate in a research study for Avago Technologies, you may be asked, for example, to evaluate prototype technologies, share impressions of marketing communications materials, or discuss aspects of our web site.

**Measuring Customer Satisfaction @ Avago Technologies**

The Avago Technologies Customer Satisfaction (CSAT) program is an ongoing, systematic study of customer experiences at key touch points across the global Avago Technologies organization. The term customer refers to: current, former, or potential customers of Avago Technologies, visitors to Avago Technologies’ web site, and resellers or channel partners working with Avago Technologies.

CSAT surveys are conducted at regular intervals using state-of-the-art web survey methodologies. Surveys are offered in multiple languages, and are designed to run smoothly on multiple operating systems and browsers.

CSAT measures your satisfaction after a recent interaction or transaction with one of Avago Technology’s customer touch points. If you recently received a survey invitation it is because you:

  * Contacted the [Avago Technical Response Center](http://support@avagotech.com/)
  * Contacted the Avago Business Center
  * Visited the Avago web site, or
  * Had recent contact with the Avago account team that supports your organization.

The customer survey process begins by sending you an e-mail invitation, sent from a senior Avago Technologies representative who is identified by name. You the recipient can contact that Avago Technologies representative to validate the study, or ask questions about the survey methodology.

**Why Avago Technologies surveys its customers**

The process of inviting customers to complete surveys is done with one overriding goal in mind: to enhance your experience with Avago Technologies.

**How often are Avago technologies CSAT surveys conducted?**

Each Avago Technologies touch point is studied twice a year so managers have up-to-date information on the customer or visitor experience at those touch points, and a clear picture of what to do to enhance your satisfaction when you interact with Avago Technologies personnel at those touch points. In research conducted with our customers on the issue of survey frequency, customers told us receiving survey invitations as often as twice a year was deemed "acceptable".

It is not our intention to survey you EVERY time you interact with one of our touch points. We use random sampling procedures and database tools to help keep the number of survey invitations sent to you under control. We understand few people actually enjoy completing surveys, but we know surveys are a valuable link between you and Avago Technologies management, and we want to keep that link open. The survey mechanism provides you a unique opportunity to speak your mind about how we are performing. Furthermore, you control whether you identify yourself or submit your comments anonymously.

At Avago Technologies, it’s always your call whether to respond when invited to participate in a survey.

**Avago Technologies ascribes to the Marketing Research Association’s Ethical Guidelines for the Use of the Internet for Conducting Opinion & Marketing Research.**

Avago Technologies is a member of the Marketing Research Association and follows the MRA Guidelines for web-based research, whose provisions include:

  * Your cooperation will be voluntary
  * Our identity will be disclosed
  * Your rights to anonymity will be safeguarded
  * Our privacy policy statements will be posted online (See items 1 through 9, above)
  * Data security is maintained
  * Unsolicited e-mail is not sent to those who have opted out of receiving such e-mail
  * For details on these Guidelines, or more information on the MRA, click here: [http://www.mra-net.org](http://www.mra-net.org/)

**Survey FAQ's**

**1\. If I agree to take this survey, will I be bombarded with more surveys from Avago Technologies?**

No. Avago Technologies is working closely with our survey research partner to limit the number of survey invitations a customer receives. Typically, you will not receive more than 2 survey invitations related to a given touch point in a 12-month period.

**2\. If I complete an Avago Technologies survey, will my contact information be sold or given to other companies for marketing or sales purposes, or used by Avago Technologies for its own marketing or sales purposes?**

No. At Avago Technologies, we take your concern for privacy seriously. Survey databases containing names and identifying information of persons who have had recent contact with Avago Technologies are never merged with marketing databases, nor shared with other parts of the Avago Technologies organization. These data are not released to third-party organizations or individuals outside the Avago Technologies organization, except to be provided to the CSAT survey research vendor who, as part of their contract with Avago Technologies, manages the process of mailing e-mail invitations to you. The CSAT vendor operates under a PERSONAL DATA CONFIDENTIALITY AGREEMENT (PDCA) with Avago Technologies, which includes the following provision, “(Vendor) may not disclose Personal Information to any other third party without the prior written consent of Avago Technologies. Under no circumstances may Participant sell, rent or lease Personal Information to any third parties.”

**3\. I was asked if I wanted to receive an Avago Technologies newsletter and opted out. Why then am I getting a survey from Avago Technologies?**

Before sending you a newsletter or marketing-related information about new Avago Technologies products or services, Avago Technologies will ask you to opt-in to confirm your interest in this information. If you elect to opt out of this type of information, no further marketing-related information will be sent to you.

The CSAT survey is a separate form of communication with our customers and channel partners, and is not classified as a marketing-related communication. It is often the concluding step in a process that began with a recent transaction or interaction with Avago Technologies. As such, the prior opt-in requirement is not relevant.

Having said that, survey participation is still voluntary. You can elect not to respond to a given survey. Our survey e-mail invitation also provides you with an means to opt-out of the entire survey process. However, if you exercise this option, you will no longer have an opportunity to share your opinions or ideas with Avago Technologies senior management through the CSAT program.

**4\. How do I know you won’t publish my name along with my responses to the CSAT survey?**

Your name or identifying data such as e-mail address, is NEVER published in CSAT reports. However, there are three scenarios where your name may appear in CSAT documents or communications, or where you may wish to provide your name in the course of completing the survey:

  * If, in the course of completing the CSAT survey, you ask Avago Technologies to follow up with you—to address a matter of concern to you, you then give our research vendor permission to forward your name and contact information to the appropriate manager at Avago Technologies to facilitate immediate follow-up and action.
  * At the conclusion of the survey, you are asked if you want to give Avago Technologies permission to “share your individual responses.” Most of our survey respondents (87%) give us permission to do so. Even when you give us permission to share your individual responses, we do not publish your name or personal identifying information in reports of findings. CSAT reports typically report findings on a touch point, regional, job-category, applications area, or product-category basis.
  * At the conclusion of some CSAT surveys, respondents are invited to provide their name and contact information for the purposes of a gift drawing, as a thank-you for completing the survey. This information is used only to make a random selection among those providing information, and to locate the winners to do gift fulfillment. Beyond these purposes, names and contact information are not released.
